Register of the Daniel Lerner collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Captured German Documents, 1944-1945 (Boxes 1-9)
  - S-File (Box 6)
    - Shortage of uniforms as far back as autumn 1943 (#222)
    - Warnings against all forms of enemy propaganda (#223)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#224)
    - Leaflets for French and foreign workers affect German soldiers (#225)
    - Investigation against German soldiers accused by enemy propaganda (#226)
    - Instructions for soldiers how to behave as POWs (#227)
    - Insufficient training of young parachutists (#228)
    - Location of German Counter-Intelligence and Security Offices in Brittany (#229)
    - Shortages of wire and equipment (#230)
    - Extracts from notes taken at General Staff school, Giessen (#231)
    - Order stating Allied superiority of equipment, fear of Allied propaganda (#232)
    - German disturbed by Allied propaganda to French doctors (#233)
    - Paris: Insecure place for Germans (#234)
    - Measures to prevent Hiwis and Volksdeutsche from deserting (#235)
    - Order re looting of cattle (#236)
    - Doenitz considers Russians best example of spiritual training (#237)
    - Eight soldiers desert in two days (#238)
    - Panzer division commanders' abilities to be tested (#239)
    - Sabotage of communications lines by German units and soldiers (#240)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#241)
    - Notes re July 20 plot (#242)
    - History, education, organization and aims of SA (#243)
    - New text of "Lilli Marlene" (#244)
    - New version of "ten little nigger boys" (#245)
    - Order of the Day for regiment going into battle in France (#246)
    - Casualty report by SS-Pz. Regt., "Der Führer" (#247)
    - Secret orders by Rundstedt re French partisans to be delivered to SD (#248)
    - Criticism of morale and attitude of sixteenth GAF Division (#249)
    - Notes of German 1st Lt. written after his capture in France (#250) (Folder 6: 6)
    - Outline of subjects of interest to the Wehrmacht propaganda (#251)
    - Rape of French girls (#252)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#253)
    - Letter describing effects of air raids on schools in Frankfurt (#254)
    - SS commissar gives his opinion of the fighting in France (#255)
    - Order re poisoned beverages for German troops, lack of clothing, etc. (#256)
    - Belgian, French, and Dutch workers resist against working for O.T. (#257)
    - Treatment of conscripted men from Polish territory (#258)
    - Faulty ammunition (#259)
    - Lists of units stationed in Holland (#260)
    - Report of invasion experiences (#261)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#262)
    - Two cases of self-mutilation, punished with death (#263)
    - Circular by Battalion Chief re Hitler plot (#264)
    - Propaganda directives: "What are we fighting for?" (#265)
    - Concern over increase of desertions (#266)
    - Increase of self-mutilation and desertions amongst parachutists (#267)
    - Bishop of Bayeux pledges himself to refrain from all political activity (#268)
    - "The diary of the End," soldier Kurt Schmeling (#269)
    - German lootings and criminal acts drive French civilians to the Fighting French (#270)
    - Kampfgruppe Bretagne dissolved (#271)
    - Extracts from letters written by members of the Waffen-SS in France (#272)
    - Battle morale (#273)
    - Farewell address of Commander of 77th Inf. Division (#274)
    - Report on meeting of German commanders from 2nd Gren. Regt. 894 (#275)
    - Activities of French partisans; countermeasures, death sentences (#276)
    - Effects of Flying Bomb (Com. Pz. Dv., "Das Reich," to his soldiers) (#277)
    - Directives for behavior as POWs given by 21st Pz. Div. (#278)
    - Attempt on Hitler's life was made "by the enemy" (NSFO) (#279)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#280)
    - Directives re handling of censorship offenses (#281)
    - Strength, battle value, and tactics of Anglo-American troops (#282)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#283)
    - Letter from Amsterdam: Dutch killing Germans, martial law in Amsterdam (#284)
    - Alarming increase of venereal diseases (#285)
    - The Führer introduces new badge for his handmen, etc. (#286)
    - Measures against "terrorists" in France (#287)
    - Increase of self-mutilation and malingering (#288)
    - Cattle and agricultural machinery to be saved before burning of houses (#289)
    - Faulty hand grenades (#290)
    - Pattern of Hitler education (#291)
    - Order re activities of French Darnand Militia (#292)
    - Increase of court martial offenses by officers and men (#293)
    - Threats against deserters - reprisals against their families (#294)
    - Desertions and lack of equipment in German foreign units (#295)
    - Activities of partisans and nationalists in France (#296)
    - Shortage of radio spare parts in the Netherlands (#297)
    - Heavy losses and lack of raw materials in the East (#298)
    - Marked decline of morale among German officers (#299)
    - Order for special lessons stressing dangerousness of Allied propaganda (#300) (Folder 6: 7)
    - Decline of discipline in the West (#301)
    - V. Kluge's declaration of loyalty to Hitler (#302)
    - Instructions to troops re treatment of Russian volunteers (#303)
    - Diary of Lt. A. Synobar (#304)
    - Stricter security measures against agents in France (#305)
    - "Kraft Brief" found on German prisoner (#306)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#307)
    - Goebbels directives to the press re "mass murder at Katyn" (#308)
    - Deserters from the Armenian Legion wanted (#309)
    - Increasing desertions by Russians in the German Army (#310)
    - Directives teaching French and Polish soldiers the German language (#311)
    - General Spang gets butter instead of margarine (#312)
    - Order of the Day urging to prevent the "enemy" from occupying St. Malo (#313)
    - Special regulations against civilian population in France (#314)
    - "Miscalculations of the Allied High Command" re invasion (#315)
    - Letter from German soldier stationed in the "Brest peninsula" (#316)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#317)
    - Dingler demands attention to supplies dropped by air to partisans (#318)
    - Order to fight French partisans mercilessly (#319)
    - Form of conditions for release by the German security police in Rennes (#320)
    - Failure of National Youth service in France (#321)
    - Increase in malingering (#322)
    - Diary of German soldier - Wegener (#323)
    - Himmler's prohibition of the word "Volksdeutscher" (#324)
    - Absence of the Luftwaffe explained to German soldiers (#325)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#326)
    - "Cunning methods" of Allied leaflets (#327)
    - Low discipline of truck drivers (#328)
    - Brutal measures against French partisans (#329)
    - Order re lack of weapons and use of captured British weapons (#330)
    - Battle experiences during invasion days - Allied superiority, etc. (#331)
    - Text of two leaflets by Germans to German troops (#332)
    - Order from Keitel re increasing offenses among officers (#333)
    - Evacuation of district of St. Malo - looting prohibited (#334)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#335)
    - Shortage of various types of materials in Panzer-Lehr Div. (#336)
    - Diary of Austrian medical sergeant Franz Anggel of Vienna (#337)
    - Hungarian and Spanish nationals in Panzer training Regt. 130 (#338)
    - SS men on burning of grain on retreat, while people at home lacked enough to eat (#339)
    - Investigations on SS men's complaining that their families do not get enough to eat (#340)
    - German officers who lose their heads (#341)
    - Falkenherst to his troops in Norway; Order of the Day re invasion (#342)
    - Diary of (Parachute) signalman (#343)
    - Atrocity propaganda re treatment of German POWs by Allies (#344)
    - Leaflet: Appeal to French youth (#345)
    - German commander on relations between German soldiers and French civilians (#346)
    - Report re relatively high losses in fighting in the West (#347)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#348)
    - Older German age groups useless in battles - desert at first opportunity (#349)
    - Directives for the fight against French forces of the interior (#350) (Folder 6: 8)
    - Hitler greeting not too much appreciated (#351)
    - Göring order in connection with July 20 plot (#352)
    - Arms dropped by British planes to be used by the Germans (#353)
    - German outline on Russian battle tactics (#354)
    - Lack of manpower forces Germans to employ engineers in front line (#355)
    - SS ordered to bring as many POWs as possible to solve manpower POW problems (#356)
    - Directives re treatment of German occupied territories (#357)
    - Ten points of instruction for German troops re treatment of POWs (#358)
    - Hitler: "The enemy has to be annihilated at the beaches" (#359)
    - Cable from the Führer (#360)
    - Six court martial cases in Pz. Lehr Div., including two suicides (#361)
    - Duplicates (#362)
    - Soldiers from Alsace desert in considerable numbers (#363)
    - Foreigners in the German Army "a danger to discipline" (#364)
    - No negotiations with "French bandits" (#365)
    - Sabotage and anti-German actions by French (#366)
    - Order of the Day: Too many Losses of Weapons - Not Enough Shooting (#367)
    - Propaganda re "incorrect treatment of German POWs" by British (#368)
    - Considerable decline of discipline among soldiers in the West (#369)
    - "Constructive" criticism on combat tactics (#370)
    - Duplicates (#371)
    - Extracts from two soldiers' letters remarks on V-2 hope for victory (#372)
    - Measures in case of sea and air invasion (#373)
    - Inquiry re membership of certain officers in Nazi Party (#374)
    - Wehrmacht prisons for foreign volunteers (#375)
    - Declarations of loyalty, von Kluge (radio) and Eberbach (#376)
    - Loss of life in SS-Pz. Div., "Hitlerjugend," through anxiousness (#377)
    - Increase of robbery in France by Germans (#378)
    - Dietrich order to overcome Allied superiority through individual heroism (#379)
    - Germans crossing into Spain lower esteem of their Division (#380)
    - German soldiers desert to Spain - shot in France (#381)
    - Five death sentences in SS unit (#382)
    - "Energetic" measures against deserters and Allied leaflets (#383)
    - Newspapers and distribution centers for Eastern volunteers (#384)
    - "The last quarter hour" (#385)
    - Circular letter on conditions in Düsseldorf (#386)
    - Front-line report on Allied propaganda (#387)
    - Increase in defeatism (#388)
    - Heavy losses through panic (#389)
    - Report on Allied landings by Major Bachus - 716th Inf. Div. (#390)
    - Rundstedt's report on the invasion of France (#391)
    - Directives for officer replacement (#392)
    - "Why the Allies are superior," report on battle experiences (#393)
    - Fighting value of Tartar legions (#394)
    - Treatment and pay of Eastern volunteers (#395)
    - Diary of German artillerymen describing retreat and capture (#396)
    - Significance of field post letters (#397)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#398)
    - Court martial for declaring the "Atlantic Wall" insufficient (#399)
    - Troops should be kept informed from day to day about situation in north and south (#399-A)
    - Precautions against desertions call for unity (#400) (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Broadcasting stations audible in the filed (#401)
    - Leaflet causing disturbance (#402)
    - Göring's appeal for the "defense of the Reich" (#403)
    - Diary revealing "Canada Spirit" (#404)
    - Systematic looting by SS (#405)
    - Cowardice in the SS (#406)
    - "Unsoldierly behavior" (#407)
    - Sabotage of communications by German troops (#408)
    - Food unfit for consumption (#409)
    - Officer to use violence against men in emergency (#410)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#411)
    - Extracts from civilian letters (#412)
    - Treatment of prisoners in the SS punishment camps (#413)
    - Sabotage activities by the French (#414)
    - Clever trick for sabotage of German mine fields by French worker (#415)
    - Hospital conditions (#416)
    - Report on Allied and German propaganda (#417)
    - Denial that Zeitzler was involved in Hitler plot - V-1 propaganda (#418)
    - Desertions in the 7th Army (#419)
    - Directive by Zeitzler for treatment of Russian deserters (#420)
    - Shortages in 2nd Pz. Div. and Pz. Gren. Regt 2 (#421)
    - Shortage of fuel (#422)
    - Rumors concerning F.P. (#423)
    - Serious decline of discipline, says Badninski (#424)
    - Directives for German civilians in German Armed Forces (#425)
    - Diary of German officer (Hitler plot, etc.) (#426)
    - Extracts from letters written to Badninski (#427)
    - Four cases of desertions by Russian volunteers and Germans (#428)
    - Directives for saving weapons and ammunition (#429)
    - Young soldiers badly trained - accidents from misuse of weapons (#430)
    - Opposition amongst Cherbourg workers causes alarm in O.T. (#431)
    - SS propaganda in German units (concerning Allied war aims) (#432)
    - Rundstedt's directive to smash invasion attempts (#433)
    - Restricted promotion for part-Jews (#434)
    - Censorship of foreigners' letters to be made known (#435)
    - Civilians to work in mine-endangered areas (#436)
    - Extracts from civilians' letters (#437)
    - Letter: Complaints about delays in payment of military allowance (#438)
    - Girl condemns organized childbirth for the Reich (#439)
    - Order by Dietrich implying mistreatment (#440)
    - Ammunition-dump explosion (#441)
    - Duplicates (#442)
    - Flying bombs on German lines (#443)
    - Neither supplies nor reserves expected (#444)
    - Figures showing increase of desertions (#445)
    - Agents to be placed amongst German troops (#446)
    - Measures against subversive activities in German Army (#447)
    - Extracts from letters by General Foltermann (#448)
    - Allied leaflets shirkers (#449)
    - Order by Colonel Aulock (#450) (Folder 7: 2)
    - Faulty ammunition (#451)
    - Shortages (#452)
    - Order for looting (#453)
    - G.A.F. Capt. accused of high treason in captivity (#454)
    - Diary of German officer assigned for "2nd line" in France (#455)
    - Nazi commissar on Allied propaganda (#456)
    - Nazi commissar's directives on Hitler plot, low morale, etc. (#457)
    - German underground leaflet (#458)
    - Badninski's address concerning hero's death (#459)
    - Musical industry moved in France (#460)
    - Order to prevent infiltration of foreign agents into German Army (#461)
    - Badninski's opinion on functions of reserves (#462)
    - Diary of Lieutenant Fasthuber (#463)
    - Diary of Austrian officer (#464)
    - Wehrmacht begging weapons from SD (#465)
    - Diary of German soldier (criticism of desertions) (#466)
    - Two diaries of German soldiers (#467)
    - German deserters will be sent to Siberia by the British (#468)
    - Distribution of leaflets amongst Allied troops (#469)
    - Duplicates (#470)
    - Battle value and tactics of British and American troops (#471)
    - Demonstrations for Allied airmen in Pas de Calais (#472)
    - Morale and treatment of Russian POWs and volunteers (#473)
    - Strict measures against desertions (#474)
    - Posts removed with help of deserters (#475)
    - Desertions and absence (#476)
    - Death sentence for surrender (#477)
    - Diary of Gren. Wurmbach (#478)
    - Letter: "The front can't hold any more" (#479)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#480)
    - Diary of German soldier (astonished about Allied materiel) (#481)
    - Nazi against Allied propaganda (#482)
    - Nazi commissar on Allied losses in the West (#483)
    - Nazi commissar warns against desertions (#484)
    - Soldiers listening to a "skillfully camouflaged" enemy broadcast (#485)
    - Nazi commissar explains "why Germany will win" (#486)
    - Nazi commissar: "Atrocity propaganda against Allies" (#487)
    - Italians: Oath of loyalty to Hitler (#488)
    - Diary of German soldier (defeatism - Allied broadcasts) (#489)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#490)
    - Extracts from POWs diary (#491)
    - Measures against families of deserters (#492)
    - SS-units keen to reach the front (#493)
    - Executions not to be photographed (#494)
    - Allied POWs "died or were shot" (#495)
    - Undermining and disintegrating influences (#496)
    - Special care for Hiwis (#497)
    - Kluge-Gersdorf conversation about withdrawal (#498)
    - Shortages revealed in various files (#499)
    - "What are we fighting for?" Book in preparation (#500) (Folder 7: 3)
    - Intentional optimism by Aulock (#501)
    - Decline of discipline in SS (#502)
    - Personal belongings of killed soldiers disappear (#503)
    - Letter by Gen. Lt. Gullmann (#504)
    - Directives for Nazi commissars re "spiritual training" (#505)
    - Directives for German front-line propaganda (#506)
    - Nazi commissar reports on morale (#507)
    - Diary of H. Karpe (#508)
    - Duplicates (#509)
    - Diary of Catholic soldier (#510)
    - Mistreatment of wounded German soldiers (#511)
    - Ramcke on discipline (#512)
    - Extremely low state of discipline in German army (#513)
    - Court martial audience dissolved (#514)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#515)
    - Punishment of officers during fighting (#516)
    - Losses of Gren. Regt. (#517)
    - Shortages of medical officers (#518)
    - Declaration of loyalty by v. Luettwitz (#519)
    - German intelligence report on French civilians (#520)
    - German soldier destroys mail from home (#521)
    - Address by Model (two copies) (#522)
    - Directives concerning Geneva conventions (#523)
    - Escaped Russian POWs join partisans (#524)
    - Names of Gestapo agents (#525)
    - Lack of trained officers for infantry (#526)
    - Defective hand grenades (#527)
    - Parachute commander on Allied leaflets re Hitler plot (#528)
    - Circular of 353 L.D. warning that Germany POWs are sent to Siberia (#529)
    - O.B. West order re new gas filter (#530)
    - V-1 that fall prematurely (#531)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#532)
    - Nazi infiltration in General staff (#533)
    - Shortage of ammunition (#534)
    - Report on retreat movements (#535)
    - Report on strength of 15th Army (#536)
    - Army Group G: Report on strength and losses (#537)
    - "Conversation with Polish-American" (#538)
    - Diary of infantry soldier (#539)
    - Rundstedt on arrest and shooting of hostages (#540)
    - Fortifications to be reinforced (#541)
    - Order on disciplinary drill (#542)
    - Investigation concerning ammunition (#543)
    - Suicides (#544)
    - Eastern volunteers returned to Stalags (#545)
    - Desertions, rape (#546)
    - Diary of Georg Seidel (#547)
    - Propaganda campaign to include Russians to desert to Germans (#548)
    - "Spirit of St. Malo" demanded from all units (#549)
    - Training with M.G. unsatisfactory (#550) (Folder 7: 4)
    - Diary of H. Steudenmaier (#551)
    - Special ceremonies for relatives of fallen soldiers (#552)
    - Directives for Nazi commissar re countering Allied propaganda (#553)
    - Extracts form soldiers' letters (#554)
    - Shortages of AA-Ammunition (#555)
    - Suicides and absence increased (#556)
    - Gas-mask filter "42" removed from secret list (#557)
    - "Impenetrable Siegfried line" (#558)
    - Hold out to the last bullet "to regain coast" (#559)
    - Change of directives for Nazi commissar (#560)
    - Shortages of paper (#560-A)
    - Secret 1000 Kg bombs (#561)
    - Diary of German soldier from signal unit (#562)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#563)
    - Defeatist letter from home garrison (#564)
    - Renewed warning against listening to Allied broadcasts (#565)
    - Custom officials engaged in Gestapo activities (#566)
    - Diary of Gefr. Wenzel (#567)
    - Divisional Commander on new Allied break-through tactics (#568)
    - Secret order by A.O.K. 15 stating ineffectiveness of fortifications (#569)
    - "Hold the position to the last wounded man" - dangerousness of Allied propaganda (#570)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#571)
    - Disaffection among Russian volunteers (#572)
    - Heavy and light weapons buried by Allied bombardments (#573)
    - Special propaganda action concerning Russians as POWs in British hands (#574)
    - Center of conspiracy against Germans in Russian emigrant circles (#575)
    - German intelligence report on sabotage in France (#576)
    - Russians accused of subversive activities (#577)
    - Interrogation of German Red X sisters returned to German lines (#578)
    - Letters to Colonel Bayer (#579)
    - Appeal by Reichsleiter Bormann re Hitler plot (#580)
    - Monthly report of German propaganda leader in France (#581)
    - List of Postleitzahlen (#582)
    - Names of SD and Gestapo men from Gestapo files in Paris (#583)
    - "Germany's food situation stable" (#584)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#585)
    - Lack of raw materials causes lack of tools (#586)
    - Hitler personally took care of defense of East Prussia (#587)
    - Goebbels does not wish the word "propaganda" used so much (#588)
    - Censorship of letters written by German soldiers (#589)
    - Laval order re behavior of French gendarmes in Allied landing makes Germans suspicious (#590)
    - Germans take special care of high-ranking Fascists in N. Italy (#591)
    - Roster of German and French Gestapo officials in Le Mans (#592)
    - List of German and French officials for Commission for Labor (#593)
    - Gestapo agents in Paris (#594)
    - Rundstedt's Order of the Day after his first dismissal (#594-A)
    - Kluge's farewell message (#595)
    - Diary of Obergefr. Selzer (#596)
    - Soldier's bombed-out wife badly treated (#597)
    - Diary of Luftwaffe lieutenant (#598)
    - Diary of German soldier coming home from Holland to France (#599)
    - Many death sentences passed on German officers (#600) (Folder 7: 5)
    - Overtired soldier sentenced to imprisonment (#601)
    - Gestapo files revealing intrigues between Vichy and the Germans (#602)
    - Retreating German soldiers spread rumors (#603)
    - Spiritual training re "Allied post-war plans" (#604)
    - Diary of German officer from the staff of General Vierow (#605)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers (#606)
    - Extracts from letters written by German civilians (#607)
    - Nazi anxiety about the "spiritual invasion of Americanism" (#608)
    - Germans shoot everyone in Labor Service uniform (#609)
    - Address by General Blaskowitz (#610)
    - Rape of 14-year old French girl by member of G.A.F. (#611)
    - New SS-card index (#612)
    - Treatment of POWs in Russia - extract from article in PDfSS (#613)
    - Duplicates (#614)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#615)
    - German woman denounces her husband to the Gestapo (#616)
    - Order to prevent Communist activities (#617)
    - German leaflets for German troops on German armament reserves (#618)
    - Principal outline of partisan fighting (#619)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#620)
    - Extracts from letters written by the Waffen-SS (#621)
    - Secret order stating unreliability of Lorrainers in German Army (#622)
    - Lack of education in German Officers' Corps (#623)
    - Flying Bomb: Revolution in aerial warfare (#624)
    - German soldier's diary - indicating effects of Allied leaflets (#625)
    - Leuna works partly destroyed (#626)
    - Diary of German N.C.O. (#627)